<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SQINC35" Name="Personal Current Transfer Receipts" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Personal income (thousands of dollars, seasonally adjusted)</Description><Definition>Consists of the income that persons receive in return for their provision of labor, land, and capital used in current production as well as other income, such as personal current transfer receipts. In the state and local personal income accounts the personal income of an area represents the income received by or on behalf of the persons residing in that area. It is calculated as the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, proprietors' income with inventory valuation (IVA) and capital consumption adjustments (CCAdj), rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj), personal dividend income, personal interest income, and personal current transfer receipts, less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>1000</Code><Description>Personal current transfer receipts</Description><Definition>Receipts of persons from government and business for which no current services are performed. Current transfer receipts from government include Social Security benefits, medical benefits, veterans' benefits, and unemployment insurance benefits. Current transfer receipts from business include liability payments for personal injury and corporate gifts to nonprofit institutions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2110</Code><Description>Social Security benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits (old-age, survivors, and disability insurance benefits) consist mainly of monthly benefits received by retired and disabled workers, dependents, and survivors and lump-sum payments received by survivors.  The state estimates are based on annual tabulations of payments from the Social Security Administration (SSA). The county estimates are based on SSA tabulations of the amount of monthly benefits paid to those in current-payment status on December 31 by county of residence of the beneficiaries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2210</Code><Description>Medicare benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits are federal government payments made through intermediaries to beneficiaries for the care provided to individuals under the provisions of the Medicare program.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2221</Code><Description>Medicaid</Description><Definition>Medicaid consists of Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) expansion under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2410</Code><Description>State unemployment insurance compensation</Description><Definition>State Unemployment Insurance Compensation consists mainly of payments received by individuals under state-administered unemployment insurance (UI) programs, but includes the special benefits authorized by Federal legislation for periods of high unemployment. The provisions that govern the eligibility, timing, and amount of the benefits vary among the states, but the provisions that govern coverage and financing are uniform nationally.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5000</Code><Description>All other personal current transfer receipts</Description><Definition>Consists of personal current transfer receipts minus Social Security benefits and Medicare benefits and Medicaid and state unemployment insurance compensation.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
